From this distant vantage point, the earth might not seem of any particular interest.
But for us, it's different.
Consider again that dot.
That's here.
That's home.
That's us.
On it, everyone you love, everyone you know,
everyone you ever heard of,
every human being who ever was,
lived out their lives.
The aggregate or joy and suffering.
Thousands of confident religions, ideologies, and economic doctrines.
Every hunter and forger, every hero and coward,
every creator and destroyer of civilization.
Every king and peasant, every young couple in love,
every mother and father, hopeful child,
inventor and explorer,
every teacher of morals, every corrupt politician,
every superstar, every supreme leader,
every saint and sinner in the history of our species,
lived there on the mode of dust, suspended in a sunbeam.
The earth is a very small stage,
in a fast cosmic arena.
Think of the rivers of blood,
spilled by all those generals and emperors.
So that in glory and triumph,
they could become the momentary masters of a fraction of a dot.
Think of the endless cruelty's visited,
by the inhabitants of one corner of the pixel,
on the scared-sleeved distinct wishable inhabitants,
but some other corner,
how frequent their misunderstandings,
how eager they are to kill one another,
how fervent their hatred.
Our pastures,
our imagines of importance,
the delusion we have some privilege to position in universe,
are challenged by this point of pale light.
Our planet is a lonely spec in the great enveloping cosmic dark.
In our obscurity, in all this vastness,
there is no hint that help who come from elsewhere,
to save us from ourselves.
The earth is the only world known so far to harbor life.
There is nowhere else, at least in the near future,
to which our species could migrate.
Visit, yes,
settle,
not yet.
Like it or not,
for the moment, the earth is where we make our stand.
It has been said that astronomy is a humbling
and character building experience.
There is perhaps no better demonstration of the folly of new inconsists,
than this distant image of our tiny world.
To me,
it underscores our responsibility to deal more kindly with one another,
and to preserve and cherish the pale blue dot.
The only one we've ever known.